<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devops on KhanhIceTea B(rain)-log</title>
    <link>https://khanhicetea.com/tags/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devops on KhanhIceTea B(rain)-log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://khanhicetea.com/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2018-02-23 : til, docker, devops</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2018-02-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2018-02-23/</guid>
      <description>DOCKER Build lightweight image by using multistage Docker is great tool to build a pull-n-run application. But sometimes, your image will be large if you build image from a big base image which has heavy compliling toolbox.
Ex:
One-stage build
FROM golang:1.9.2 WORKDIR /go/src/github.com/khanhicetea/test/ COPY . . RUN CGO_ENABLED=0 GOOS=linux go build . ENTRYPOINT [&amp;quot;/go/src/github.com/khanhicetea/test/test&amp;quot;]  Multi-stage builds
FROM golang:1.9.2 WORKDIR /go/src/github.com/khanhicetea/test/ COPY . . RUN CGO_ENABLED=0 GOOS=linux go build .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2018-01-22 : til, sysadmin, ansible, logging, devops</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2018-01-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2018-01-22/</guid>
      <description>DEVOPS Ansible running host pattern Ansible supports pattern to select and filter running hosts from all hosts. Here is some common pattern
 * : wildcard, standalone mean all group1,group2 : run hosts belong to group1 or group2 *.web : run hosts belongs to group matches pattern. Ex: backend.web, frontend.web all:!abc : run all hosts exclude hosts belongs to group abc   Infrastructure by code ;)
 SYSADMIN Use journalctl to check system logs Logging and Monitoring are important factor for system admin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-11-22 : ci, git, workflow, devops, automation, til, docker</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-11-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-11-22/</guid>
      <description>DOCKER Reduce init time MySQL docker image Original MySQL docker image uses a script to generate ssl certificates for service. Sometime we don&amp;rsquo;t really need it (connect via a docker network link or need a fast enough database service to build a automated test).
We can reduce init time by removing the script from original Docker image
FROM mysql:5.7 # Remove mysql_ssl_rsa_setup to ignore setup SSL certs RUN rm -f /usr/bin/mysql_ssl_rsa_setup   FAST as a FEATURE !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-10-13 : ci, database, devops, indexes, til, netcat</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-10-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-10-13/</guid>
      <description>DATABASE Indexes on multiple columns Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have an indexes on 2 columns (A, B) of the table (X). So this is three use cases happen :
 You query data based on both of 2 columns =&amp;gt; Indexes will be considered You query data based on (A) =&amp;gt; Indexes will be considered You query data based on (B) =&amp;gt; Indexes will be ignored because database indexes your data by B-tree algo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-08-04 : python, devops, free, til, heroku, http2, requests</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-08-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-08-04/</guid>
      <description>DEVOPS Free sandbox server for development We can use Heroku as a forever-free sandbox solution for testing or hosting micro service. Adding a credit card to have 1000 free computing hours.
Heroku will make a service down if no received request come. We can use a cronjob-like service to check service health and keep it live !!! ;)
Cronjob check health SASS : pingdom, statuscake, port-monitor, uptimerobot
Btw, I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend you keep service live but no use, it makes Heroku infrastructure heavy and THAT&amp;rsquo;S NOT FAIR for them !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-05-19 : sysadmin, shell, testing, devops, til, automated, bash</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-19/</guid>
      <description>DEVOPS Checking forced push conflicts on source code in auto testing Using automated CI solution likes Travis, Jenkins, DroneCI, &amp;hellip; is good solution to ensure quality of software and no breaks in deployment.
Sometimes, developers force push conflicts part to production branch of source code. If the CI tests only backend (python, ruby, php, go, ..) and forget about frontend code, then your application will be exploded !
So checking the conflicts code is required step before testing backend and deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kick start Docker environment on ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/kick-start-docker-environment-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 14:19:39 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/kick-start-docker-environment-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>What does script do :
 Install latest Docker Engine Install latest Docker Compose tool AND last but not least, a congratuation message !  Here is the script :
  Hm.. it&amp;rsquo;s exactly docker images are building instead
 Ref:
 Docker meme from developermemes.com  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kick start a LEMP stack on Ubuntu 16.04</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/kick-start-a-lemp-stack-on-ubuntu-16-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:21:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/kick-start-a-lemp-stack-on-ubuntu-16-04/</guid>
      <description>LEMP = Linux + EngineX(NginX) + MySQL + PHP
 Too tired for doing same tasks over and over again. I made this script to help me (and you) on kicking start a new LEMP stack on production server. Hope it useful !
What does script do :
 Disable IPv6 (it&amp;rsquo;s not ready for production at the moment) Configure firewall (only accepts port 22, 80 and 443) Disable password authentication to SSH service Upgrade system Install useful tools (git, screen, vim, curl and lego for LetsEncrypt ACME) NginX MySQL 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to reload gracefully supervisor program</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/how-to-reload-gracefully-supervisor-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 13:59:26 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/how-to-reload-gracefully-supervisor-program/</guid>
      <description>Problem We have some managed worker-programs by supervisor. While deploying new codebase of worker, we have to restart them to update new logic.
But it&amp;rsquo;s creepy when supervisor kills all processes of programs and starts again.
WHAT IF IT KILLS A WORKING WORKER ?
Of course, the working task will be fucked up. Database transaction, database migration, sending email and other scheduled tasks will be crashed in middle. Some tasks can&amp;rsquo;t not be reserved, rollbacked or re-runned.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>