<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on KhanhIceTea B(rain)-log</title>
    <link>https://khanhicetea.com/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on KhanhIceTea B(rain)-log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://khanhicetea.com/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2018-02-21 : til, networking, vim</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2018-02-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2018-02-21/</guid>
      <description>NETWORKING List opening ports or listening UNIX sockets In Linux, you can use netstat to list all opening ports and listening UNIX sockets
$ sudo netstat -npl  Tip to remember command : network stattistic - natual languge processing
;)
VIM Convert tabs to spaces This is my config to use 4 spaces instead tab
filetype plugin indent on set tabstop=4 set shiftwidth=4 set expandtab  To convert existing file from tabs to spaces, use this command</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2018-01-16 : til, firewall, security, networking, linux</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2018-01-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2018-01-16/</guid>
      <description>LINUX Disable IPv6 to stop getting stuck in network I know IPv6 will be future for networking, but at this moment &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s suck !&amp;rdquo; :(
Some service will be failed when trying to connect IPv6 destination :
 apt package manager smtp curl  So I decided to disable IPv6 on every production server.
$ echo &amp;quot;net.ipv6.conf.all.disable_ipv6 = 1&amp;quot; | sudo tee -a /etc/sysctl.conf $ echo &amp;quot;net.ipv6.conf.default.disable_ipv6 = 1&amp;quot; | sudo tee -a /etc/sysctl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-10-07 : til, sysadmin, tool, networking</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-10-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-10-07/</guid>
      <description>SYSADMIN Using netcat as tiny TCP debug tool You can use netcat or nc as a debugging TCP tool. It can be a TCP sender and receiver with a short session (auto close when connection is closed)
Examples :
Scan ports
$ nc -zv 127.0.0.1 20-80  Check redis status
$ echo &#39;info&#39; | nc 127.0.0.1 6379  Retrieve http response
$ printf &amp;quot;GET /xinchao HTTP/1.1\r\n\r\n&amp;quot; | nc 127.0.0.1 8000 | tee xinchao.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-10-04 : sysadmin, networking, smtp, til, time, mail, cpu</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-10-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-10-04/</guid>
      <description>NETWORKING How SMTP works When a email send through an SMTP (with authentication), every SMTP server is a hop in mail routing. So it will transfer to localmail or forward the email to next hop (shortest distance via DNS MX record).
And standard port of SMTP is 25 (unsecured, but can upgrade to TLS via STARTTLS command).
$ nslookup -type=mx gmail.com 8.8.8.8 Server: 8.8.8.8 Address: 8.8.8.8#53 Non-authoritative answer: gmail.com mail exchanger = 20 alt2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-09-25 : sysadmin, networking, zip, firewall, compress, til, tools</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-25/</guid>
      <description>SYSADMIN Blocking specified country to prevent from DDOS Last day I checked system logs and got a lot of warning messages mentioned that my server has been attack via Brute-force. So I decided to blocked some countries from connecting to attacked ports (21, 25). They are China, Russia and US.
This site provides a list of IP blocks of specified country
http://www.ipdeny.com/ipblocks/
TOOLS Zip compressing list of files To specify a list of compressed files when using zip cli tool, you could use -@ [file_list] flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-09-07 : til, sysadmin, networking</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-07/</guid>
      <description>NETWORKING TCP FIN timeout The TCP FIN timeout belays the amount of time a port must be inactive before it can reused for another connection. The default is often 60 seconds, but can normally be safely reduced to 30 or even 15 seconds:
net.ipv4.tcp_fin_timeout = 15  Ref : https://www.linode.com/docs/web-servers/nginx/configure-nginx-for-optimized-performance
SYSADMIN Generate dhparam file faster openssl uses strong prime (which is useless for security but requires an awful lot more computational effort.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>