<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KhanhIceTea B(rain)-log</title>
    <link>https://khanhicetea.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on KhanhIceTea B(rain)-log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 15:50:00 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://khanhicetea.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Webpack Basics in 2 days</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/xiny/how-i-learn-webpack-basics-in-2-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 15:50:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/xiny/how-i-learn-webpack-basics-in-2-days/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Learn from https://webpack.js.org/guides/getting-started/
Clone my repo to follow commit hash by section : https://github.com/khanhicetea/learn-n-earn
Day 1 ,  webpack.config.js
const path = require(&#39;path&#39;); module.exports = { entry: &#39;./src/index.js&#39;, output: { filename: &#39;bundle.js&#39;, path: path.resolve(__dirname, &#39;dist&#39;) } };  Bash
$ ./node_modules/.bin/webpack --config webpack.config.js  Learned
 entry : start point to dive in dependency graph. output : output after pack the web modules  filename : bundle filename path : dist path   Day 2 Import assets ,   CSS file : use style-loader and css-loader Image file : use file-loader WebFont file : use file-loader Data file use json-loader, xml-loader or csv-loader  module: { rules: [ { test: /\.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-10-04</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-10-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-10-04/</guid>
      <description>NETWORKING How SMTP works When a email send through an SMTP (with authentication), every SMTP server is a hop in mail routing. So it will transfer to localmail or forward the email to next hop (shortest distance via DNS MX record).
And standard port of SMTP is 25 (unsecured, but can upgrade to TLS via STARTTLS command).
$ nslookup -type=mx gmail.com 8.8.8.8 Server: 8.8.8.8 Address: 8.8.8.8#53 Non-authoritative answer: gmail.com mail exchanger = 20 alt2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#LEBY : Động từ</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/leby/verb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 19:37:06 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/leby/verb/</guid>
      <description>Định nghĩa Động từ (verb) diễn tả những gì mà danh từ (người, vật) làm hoặc diễn ra.
 Một hành động (action) : run, hit Một sự kiện (event) : snow, marry Một tình huống, trạng thái (situation) : be, seem, have Một sự thay đổi (change) : become, develop, shrink  Và về bản chất ngôn ngữ, động từ được gọi là động (move, change, happen) thì luôn luôn phải chịu ảnh hưởng bởi một nhân tố tuyến tính là thời gian (time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMTPor : Dead simple SMTP testing tool</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/smtpor-dead-simple-smtp-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 22:26:54 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/smtpor-dead-simple-smtp-testing/</guid>
      <description>Never need a bigass mail client to test your SMTP config !
 Github Repo : https://github.com/khanhicetea/smtpor
Demo TL;DR Using Docker to run
$ docker run -d -p 3000:3000 khanhicetea/smtpor  Then open http://localhost:3000 to try a shot !
Install &amp;amp; Start $ npm install $ npm start  Heroku Deploying $ heroku login $ heroku git:remote -a [your-app-name] $ git push heroku master  Contributors  @khanhicetea  License MIT License</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading NFC Card ID on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/reading-nfc-card-id-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 17:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/reading-nfc-card-id-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites Install driver My device is ACS122U : http://www.acs.com.hk/en/products/3/acr122u-usb-nfc-reader/#tab_downloads
Kernel modules # echo &amp;quot;uinput&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/modules # echo &amp;quot;install nfc /bin/false&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/modprobe.d/blacklist.conf # echo &amp;quot;install pn533 /bin/false&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/modprobe.d/blacklist.conf  Install packages sudo apt-get install swig libccid pcscd libpcsclite-dev libpcsclite1 python-dev python-pip gcc linux-headers-$(uname -r)  Run service sudo service pcscd restart  Install python packages sudo pip install pyscard python-uinput evdev  Source code This is source code that read the card ID and simulate keystrokes to type card ID by text then pressing ENTER key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-09-27</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-27/</guid>
      <description>LINUX Send ENTER key to kernel When you try to send an Enter keyboard to linux kernel, it looks like nothing happens.
This is because you only send a key press (KEY DOWN) but don&amp;rsquo;t send an key release (KEY UP) event after that.
SYSADMIN BASH tracing commands Thank Hiro Ishii for teaching me this
set -x will print all running commands in your bash script
So I dove in and look for all set options of BASH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-09-26</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-26/</guid>
      <description>SYSADMIN BASH exiting on first error Setting a flag set -e to bash script will let the script exit on first error occurs, so if you want to ignore a command just adding || true to suffix
set -e errorCmd $1 || true echo &amp;quot;Run here !&amp;quot;  And opposite of set -e is set +e, haha of course !
set +e errorCmd $1 echo &amp;quot;Still run here !&amp;quot;  SYSADMIN BASH return a value in function Creating function is a good way to refactor your bash script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-09-25</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-25/</guid>
      <description>SYSADMIN Blocking specified country to prevent from DDOS Last day I checked system logs and got a lot of warning messages mentioned that my server has been attack via Brute-force. So I decided to blocked some countries from connecting to attacked ports (21, 25). They are China, Russia and US.
This site provides a list of IP blocks of specified country
http://www.ipdeny.com/ipblocks/
TOOLS Zip compressing list of files To specify a list of compressed files when using zip cli tool, you could use -@ [file_list] flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-09-07</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-07/</guid>
      <description>NETWORKING TCP FIN timeout The TCP FIN timeout belays the amount of time a port must be inactive before it can reused for another connection. The default is often 60 seconds, but can normally be safely reduced to 30 or even 15 seconds:
net.ipv4.tcp_fin_timeout = 15  Ref : https://www.linode.com/docs/web-servers/nginx/configure-nginx-for-optimized-performance
SYSADMIN Generate dhparam file faster openssl uses strong prime (which is useless for security but requires an awful lot more computational effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-09-05</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-05/</guid>
      <description>SYSADMIN Ansible playbook : skip to task You can skip to a task by its name by adding parameter --start-at
$ ansible-playbook playbook.yml --start-at=&amp;quot;[your task name]&amp;quot;  SYSADMIN Grep : find a string in folder Grep is a greate tool for searching a string in files.
Syntax
$ grep -nr &#39;[string]&#39; [folder]  If you want to show surrounding lines the result, add flag -C [number] to the command</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-09-01</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-01/</guid>
      <description>MYSQL Mycli : a new good cli MySql Client This tool is written in Python with super cool features (auto-complete and colors).
Worth a shot !
Install
$ pip install mycli  Usage
$ mycli -h 127.0.0.1 -P 3306 -u root  Screencast
SYSADMIN Create SSH tunnel manually SSH Tunnel is a fast way to transfer traffic through unsafe internet today. It would be used in MySQL connect, FTP connect or HTTP connect, &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#LEBY : Danh Từ</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/leby/noun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 23:59:18 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/leby/noun/</guid>
      <description>Định nghĩa Danh từ là từ nhằm trả lời câu hỏi &amp;ldquo;Cái gì ?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Đứa nào ?&amp;rdquo; hoặc &amp;ldquo;Ở đâu ?&amp;rdquo;
Ví dụ như :
 &amp;ldquo;Mày đang cầm cái gì ?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Cái gì càng nặng càng nhẹ ?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Đứa nào hái hoa vườn này ?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Thằng nào viết cái này ?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Tối nay ăn ở đâu ?&amp;rdquo;  Danh từ được dùng để đặt tên nhằm để xác định một thực thể, một thứ gì đó trừu cmn tượng, hoặc một cái mà con người chưa nghĩa ra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#LEBY : Loại từ trong tiếng Anh</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/leby/word-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 23:49:21 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/leby/word-classes/</guid>
      <description>Các lớp (loại) từ trong tiếng Anh Như đã được đề cập ở bài trước, 26 chữ cái A-Z đứng gần nhau hoặc có thể cách nhau dấu gạch ngang đã cấu tạo nên những từ ngữ phong phú và đa dạng.
Hiện tại ta chia làm 8 loại từ chính.
   # Loại từ Tên tiếng Việt Viết tắt Ví dụ     1 Noun Danh từ (n) human, dog, tree, happiness, money, &amp;hellip;   2 Verb Động từ (v) walk, love, be, grow, &amp;hellip;   3 Adjective Tính từ (adj) blue, slow, tall, Vietnamese, handsome, &amp;hellip;   4 Adverb Trạng từ (adv) fastly, very, really, nearly, &amp;hellip;   5 Pronoun Đại từ (pro) I, we, you, they, he, she, it, that, this, him, .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#LEBY : Chữ cái trong tiếng Anh</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/leby/english-alphabet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 22:35:23 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/leby/english-alphabet/</guid>
      <description>Hệ thống chữ cái Mọi ngôn ngữ ghi chép đều cần một bảng chữ cái. Có hai hệ thống chữ cái là :
 Chữ tượng hình (mỗi ký tự đại diện cho một khái niệm) : chữ Ai-cập, chữ Hán, &amp;hellip; nôm na là mấy chữ nhìn như con giun í Chữ tượng thanh (mỗi ký tự đại diện cho một âm) : chữ Latin, chữ Ả-rập hay chữ Hindu, &amp;hellip; thường được tiến hóa từ chữ tượng hình  Rất may là chữ tiếng Anh và chữ tiếng Việt đều theo hệ Latin nên được hưởng sái chữ tượng thanh (tiến hóa hơn, dễ dàng hơn).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#LEBY : Giới thiệu</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/leby/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 23:59:59 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/leby/intro/</guid>
      <description>NÓI TRƯỚC BƯỚC SẼ QUA : sê-ri #LEBY này sẽ hoàn toàn viết bằng ngôn ngữ tiếng Việt đẹp đẽ của dân tộc Việt, ngoài ra nó sẽ có một số từ hơi dân dã, hoang dã và đôi khi hơi buôn thả nên các bạn nên lưu ý trước khi đọc. Nếu có thấy khó chịu bởi ngôn từ thì &amp;hellip;. cũng kệ chứ biết sao giờ !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webfonts Optimization Using Nginx</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/webfonts-optimization-using-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 22:56:05 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/webfonts-optimization-using-nginx/</guid>
      <description>Context Everytime you decided to use a webfont on your web, you think about Google Web Fonts, which is the best CDN for webfonts at this moment.
So why Google Fonts is good solution : - Have many popular and updated fonts - Global CDN - Easy UX to get started - Auto detects user&amp;rsquo;s browser then return supported font type (TTF, WOFF or WOFF2)
But  It&amp;rsquo;s a tracking endpoint (collect data to Google) Network latency (you have a CDN in your country)  Solution We use a simple Node server and NGINX with proxy cache mod to resolve this case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-08-10</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-08-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-08-10/</guid>
      <description>JAVASCRIPT Eval function and with block JS code will be slower if engine detects any of &amp;lsquo;eval&amp;rsquo; function or &amp;lsquo;with&amp;rsquo; block b/c compiler stop optimizing the code
JAVASCRIPT Scope and Closure Run this code
for (var i=1; i&amp;lt;=5; i++) { setTimeout( function timer(){ console.log( i ); }, i*1000 ); }  What you expected
1 2 3 4 5  But, result is
6 6 6 6 6  Solution is</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-08-08</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-08-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-08-08/</guid>
      <description>LINUX Remap Capslock to Control key Edit file /etc/default/keyboard and set
XKBOPTIONS=&amp;quot;ctrl:nocaps&amp;quot;  Then, logout and log in again to impact
WEB Ping Google to crawl updated content When you post new content to your website, the fastest way is ping search engines to notify them. After that, they will try to crawl and index your page.
One way to ping search engines is using XMLRPC ping
This is a example XMLRPC request (HTTP POST request with xml body)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-08-06</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-08-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-08-06/</guid>
      <description>JAVA Runing old java applets on brower Mostly morden browser has stop support Java plugins, so you can&amp;rsquo;t run Java applet on browser.
Temporary way : - run in IE or Safari - run in an old Firefox (version 23)
And what if old java applet can&amp;rsquo;t be runned on Java 8 because of weak signature algorithm. Try this
 Open java.security file :  In MacOS, located in /Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/jdk[jdk-version].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-08-04</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-08-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-08-04/</guid>
      <description>DEVOPS Free sandbox server for development We can use Heroku as a forever-free sandbox solution for testing or hosting micro service. Adding a credit card to have 1000 free computing hours.
Heroku will make a service down if no received request come. We can use a cronjob-like service to check service health and keep it live !!! ;)
Cronjob check health SASS : pingdom, statuscake, port-monitor, uptimerobot
Btw, I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend you keep service live but no use, it makes Heroku infrastructure heavy and THAT&amp;rsquo;S NOT FAIR for them !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Câu đố vui toán học ngu ngốc</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-riddle-about-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 22:49:08 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-riddle-about-number/</guid>
      <description>Lâu rùi không viết &amp;hellip;
Câu đố nhức nách Ngày xửa ngày xưa, ngay tại cái thời mà ông tổ ông tô sáng tạo nên những con số dùng để đếm, rồi dần dần để tính toán và để &amp;hellip; hơn thua. Ngày đó có một cậu bé nọ ở trong xóm trọ, cậu hỏi họ một câu đố rất là nhức xọ. 🙀💀 Câu đố đấy nôm na như sau :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Week #19</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 23:59:59 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-19/</guid>
      <description>Random birthday Last week, I turned to 25. I had a small dinner with my family, that is all I need on that day. Btw, it was just a normal day likes every single day.
The reason of the feeling is every day, when I can take breath, feel the pains, hear the sounds, eat a pie, talk to people and think about random things. It is a special and wonderful day !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-06-15</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-06-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-06-15/</guid>
      <description>SYSADMIN Gearman bash worker and client Gearman is a awesome job queue service that helps you scale your system. In smaller context, it can help us to run a background woker for minor tasks like backup data, cleaning system.
Install :
$ sudo apt install gearman-job-server gearman-tools  Create a worker bash script
worker.sh
#!/bin/bash echo $1 echo $2  Run worker, -w means run as worker mode , -f test means function name will be test</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-06-13</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-06-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-06-13/</guid>
      <description>GIT Resolving conflict like a boss When using git merge new branch to old branch, you just want use all ours or theirs version but be lazy to update every conflicted file.
grep -lr &#39;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&#39; . | xargs git checkout --ours  Or
grep -lr &#39;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&#39; . | xargs git checkout --theirs  Explain : these commands will find any file contains &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; string (conflicted file) and run git checkout --[side]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #18</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 17:49:53 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-18/</guid>
      <description>Random nights Last wednesday night, after having dinner, going around and enjoying traffic jam in Sai Gon. I stopped in front of Le Van Tam park (the most beautiful park in there).
Walked 2 rounds the park, took a deep breath and enjoyed the border between silence in park and noise on street. It made me feel I was living, but not existing.
Stepped in center of the park, there were a lot of activities (hiphop, skating, working out, dancing, &amp;hellip;) by people from kids to teenagers and even old men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #17 : EAK</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:15:06 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-17/</guid>
      <description> Random suffix I have no idea why many words end with &amp;ldquo;-EAK&amp;rdquo; means negative
We are wEAK We brEAK It&#39;s blEAK We frEAK out Feelings lEAK Things unspEAK ... Finally, we need a brEAK  Random busy week Nopeeeee, it&amp;rsquo;s not busy. I&amp;rsquo;m just WEAK !
Random song   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #16</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 23:59:59 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-16/</guid>
      <description>Random things  Everything is nothing
 You got everything means you had nothing.
 Nothing is something
 You had nothing means you got something (it is NOTHING)
 So something is &amp;hellip; everything
 Sometimes you got something means you had everything, and lost something means lost everything.
Something is mostly the BELIEF
Transitive Property of Equality : If a = b and b = c then a = c</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-05-24</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-24/</guid>
      <description>DOCKER Changing channel from alpha to stable will remove ALL DATA On MacOS, changing Docker channel will remove all data (includes volumes, images, networks and &amp;hellip; everything).
Because Docker on Mac using a minimal Linux machine to host docker engine, so changing machine means discarding all old data. So BECAREFUL !
DOCKER Reducing docker image the right way When building an image, Docker engine commit file system layer on every command (RUN, ADD, COPY).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-05-22</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-22/</guid>
      <description>SYSADMIN Using BSD find util to find and exec command on file and folder Simple syntax of find
$ find [find_path] -type [file_type] -exec [command] {} \;  Add filename matching pattern to filter the result
$ find [find_path] -name &amp;quot;*.php&amp;quot; -type [file_type] -exec [command] {} \;  Where file_type is :
 b : block special c : character special d : directory f : regular file l : symbolic link p : FIFO s : socket  Examples:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #15</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 22:56:20 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-15/</guid>
      <description>Random article Last day, I read a random article on Hacker News - &amp;ldquo;Slow the fuck down&amp;rdquo;. Yah, interesting title lead me to read it because of curious. (Actually, I like to read any article contains &amp;ldquo;fuck&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;shit&amp;rdquo;) 😝
The best say I really really love is
 You’re busy because you’re weak.
 I will translate it to Vietnamese when I create some free time.
Random idea I&amp;rsquo;m bad in English for sharing (sharing requires writing and speaking).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-05-19</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-19/</guid>
      <description>DEVOPS Checking forced push conflicts on source code in auto testing Using automated CI solution likes Travis, Jenkins, DroneCI, &amp;hellip; is good solution to ensure quality of software and no breaks in deployment.
Sometimes, developers force push conflicts part to production branch of source code. If the CI tests only backend (python, ruby, php, go, ..) and forget about frontend code, then your application will be exploded !
So checking the conflicts code is required step before testing backend and deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-05-18</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-18/</guid>
      <description>SYSADMIN Grant user to use sudo without password This is bad practice but it&amp;rsquo;s kind of hacky thing if you YOLO
# Create a user with home dir and bash shell (if you don&#39;t have yet) $ useradd -m YOURUSERNAME -s /bin/bash $ sudo vi /etc/sudoers  Add this line below root ALL=(ALL:ALL) ALL (User privilege specification section)
$ YOUR_USERNAME ALL=(ALL:ALL) NOPASSWD:ALL  Then press :wq! to force saving the file</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-05-17</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-17/</guid>
      <description>MYSQL Mysql dumping only table structure Adding -D to dump only data structure
Example :
$ mysqldump -h 127.0.0.1 -u root -p&amp;quot;something&amp;quot; -D database1 &amp;gt; db.sql  SYSADMIN Compressing and Extracting files with rar in Linux zip and tar disadvantages All unicode filename will be transform to weird character, so it makes broken paths and broken links
Notice rar and unrar in Linux isn&amp;rsquo;t same version and so don&amp;rsquo;t use unrar to extract archived file by rar (It causes invalid full paths)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #14</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 23:32:02 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-14/</guid>
      <description>Random routine Switching new living place, I have to do something by myself :
 Ironing clothes Washing disks Cleaning room  I hadn&amp;rsquo;t done these jobs for long time. They consume my time, energy but make me feel more freedom, more love in my parents.
Random talk Having a talking diner with my boss, I learnt how to become a management guy.
 Firstly, I have to reduce my expectation on people in what I can&amp;rsquo;t change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning thought #1 : MAGIC !</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/lightning-thought-1-magic-in-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 23:01:53 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/lightning-thought-1-magic-in-software/</guid>
      <description>Random quote  “Insanity: doing the same thing over and over again and expecting different results.” - Albert Einstein
 It&amp;rsquo;s true in LOGIC ! But sometimes, it goes wrong in computer science and &amp;hellip; life.
What does computer program do ? We learnt from Computer Science courses this phisolophy :
 PROGRAM takes INPUT and produces OUTPUT
So, same PROGRAM + same INPUT = same OUTPUT
 And that&amp;rsquo;s the basis of every testing techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #13</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 22:49:12 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-13/</guid>
      <description>Random number Wow, I wrote 13 crazy articles about my random life. The first though came in my head is &amp;ldquo;let search about this crazy number&amp;rdquo;. And this is what I got :
 The sixth prime number, now I got why people hate 13th day in Friday. A Happy Number, lol in Math only. One of Pythagorean triple. (5, 12, 13). This 13th May 2017, 100 years of Virgin of Fatima Unlucky number in many cultures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #12</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 22:30:30 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-12/</guid>
      <description>RANDOM FLOWER  THE LAST FLOWER WAS FALLEN
(THE TIME MADE IT)
  OR JUST BE EATEN.
(THE SHEEP MADE IT)
  WHO KNOWS ?!??
BTW, I PREFER THE FOX OVER IT.
 RANDOM SONG   OMG ! OMG ! It&amp;rsquo;s HANS ZIMMER song ! The whole playlist here
 REMEMBER : NEVER EVER &amp;hellip; ASK SOMEONE &amp;hellip; TO DRAW YOU &amp;hellip; A SHEEP ! HAHA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-04-25</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-04-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-04-25/</guid>
      <description>DATABASE Basics about sqlite command line tool We can use sqlite3 command line tool to run SQL statement in sqlite3 file.
View all table : .tables Truncate table : delete from [table_name]; then run vacuum; to clear space Close : press Ctrl ^ D to escape $ sqlite3 database.sqlite SQLite version 3.8.10.2 2015-05-20 18:17:19 Enter &amp;quot;.help&amp;quot; for usage hints. sqlite&amp;gt; .tables auth_group backend_church auth_group_permissions backend_masstime auth_permission django_admin_log auth_user django_content_type auth_user_groups django_migrations auth_user_user_permissions django_session backend_area sqlite&amp;gt; select * from auth_user; 1|pbkdf2_sha256$30000$QQSOJMiXmNly$mWUlYwZnaQGsv9UVZcdTb29P7IHrgnd7ja3T/uwFqvw=|2017-03-25 15:06:40.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kick start Docker environment on ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/kick-start-docker-environment-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 14:19:39 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/kick-start-docker-environment-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>What does script do :
 Install latest Docker Engine Install latest Docker Compose tool AND last but not least, a congratuation message !  Here is the script :
  Hm.. it&amp;rsquo;s exactly docker images are building instead
 Ref:
 Docker meme from developermemes.com  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #11</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 00:01:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-11/</guid>
      <description>Today, in church, the priest said
 &amp;ldquo;Đời vốn đã khổ, vì thế đừng làm khổ nhau hơn nữa. Thay vào đó hãy làm nó vui hơn - hạnh phúc hơn !&amp;rdquo;
 This week, there is a story make me think about :
Last 2 days, my high school friend, &amp;hellip;. committed suicide. He wasn&amp;rsquo;t my close friend and rarely talked with him but he was a good man. When I heard about him, I felt emptiness, no feeling (Is my soul cold ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-04-21</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-04-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-04-21/</guid>
      <description>HTTP ab failed responses When benchmarking a HTTP application server using ab tool, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t only care about how many requests per second, but percentage of Success responses.
A notice that you must have the same content-length in responses, because ab tool will assume response having different content-length from Document Length (in ab result) is failed response.
Example
Webserver using Flask
from flask import Flask from random import randint app = Flask(__name__) @app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #10</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 12:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-10/</guid>
      <description>HAPPY EASTER !!!
Blessed are those who believe without seeing me. - John 20:29
 Random stupid idea Last week, I find out that my stupid phone (BlackBerry 9900) deleted automaticly old SMS messages (30-day period). Oh shit ! How can they have that stupid idea, deleting user data without confirmation. It&amp;rsquo;s nightmare ! That&amp;rsquo;s why they failed in smartphone market nowaday, old-stupid idea in new era.
Btw, hmm&amp;hellip; It may be good to me !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kick start a LEMP stack on Ubuntu 16.04</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/kick-start-a-lemp-stack-on-ubuntu-16-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:21:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/kick-start-a-lemp-stack-on-ubuntu-16-04/</guid>
      <description>LEMP = Linux + EngineX(NginX) + MySQL + PHP
 Too tired for doing same tasks over and over again. I made this script to help me (and you) on kicking start a new LEMP stack on production server. Hope it useful !
What does script do :
 Disable IPv6 (it&amp;rsquo;s not ready for production at the moment) Configure firewall (only accepts port 22, 80 and 443) Disable password authentication to SSH service Upgrade system Install useful tools (git, screen, vim, curl and lego for LetsEncrypt ACME) NginX MySQL 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #9</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 22:27:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-9/</guid>
      <description>This week, my mind is overloaded. Feeling, family, work, opportunity, choice and useless thoughts.
ALL WE NEED IS A FULL SLEEP
AFTER WAKING UP YOURSELF, REMEMBER 3 THINGS
BEING KIND
BEING KIND TO YOURSELF
DRINK ENOUGH WATER
and
Don&amp;rsquo;t try to disconnect, we were born for connecting
  Ref:
 Cover photo from askpergers&amp;rsquo;s wordpress  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #8</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:27:41 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-8/</guid>
      <description>Random trip Last week, I had a trip to Da Nang city with my friends (and my business partners). It&amp;rsquo;s a nice trip, beautiful places, good food and yeah &amp;hellip; cool experience.
In this city, I met a 73-year-old man (wife-father of my friend) who inspired me about works and life.
I asked myself, could I live good as him at that age ? Or still stuck in my small circle ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #7</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 20:26:58 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-7/</guid>
      <description>Random luck Five days ago, while I was riding bike at 50km/h, one &amp;ldquo;cute&amp;rdquo; stone hit my head. I was shocked and didn&amp;rsquo;t know what was going on. After calming down and slowing down the bike, I told to myself &amp;ldquo;Oh shit ! It&amp;rsquo;s fucking bad and hurt ! How can I continue to ride ? Would I lost my mind ? GOD please help me !&amp;rdquo;.
After 10-minute feeling the pain and thinking about my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to reload gracefully supervisor program</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/how-to-reload-gracefully-supervisor-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 13:59:26 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/how-to-reload-gracefully-supervisor-program/</guid>
      <description>Problem We have some managed worker-programs by supervisor. While deploying new codebase of worker, we have to restart them to update new logic.
But it&amp;rsquo;s creepy when supervisor kills all processes of programs and starts again.
WHAT IF IT KILLS A WORKING WORKER ?
Of course, the working task will be fucked up. Database transaction, database migration, sending email and other scheduled tasks will be crashed in middle. Some tasks can&amp;rsquo;t not be reserved, rollbacked or re-runned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #6 : Hope vs Expectation</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 21:02:55 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-6/</guid>
      <description>RANDOM WORD OF WEEK Exceptation : rigid clinging to unreal belief
Kỳ vọng : sự bám víu vào niềm tin không thực
RANDOM ARTICLE The Difference Between Expectation and Hope, this is original link
Below is my miss-taken Vietnamese version
SỰ KHÁC NHAU GIỮA HY VỌNG VÀ KỲ VỌNG CHÚNG TA KỲ VỌNG CÁI GÌ Lúc tôi làm bác sỹ chỉnh hình bệnh viện nội trú, mỗi đêm trôi qua thật là dài và khó khăn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Week #5 (truly)</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-5-truly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:30:15 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-5-truly/</guid>
      <description>STOP THINKING, JUST &amp;hellip; LIVE
 This week article is short because I left something behind. I just closed a door.
 WHEN A DOOR CLOSES, ANOTHER ONE OPENS - Graham Bell
 Yeap, I think it&amp;rsquo;s true. And, it happens today &amp;hellip; Should I try next door ?
Sure, whatever happens, it&amp;rsquo;s WORTH A SHOT !
  Some will stay,
Some want to leave.
I roam around, around</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ở đời, hơn thua được gì - mất chi</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/o-doi-hon-thua-duoc-gi-mat-chi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 01:05:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/o-doi-hon-thua-duoc-gi-mat-chi/</guid>
      <description>Hơn thua là gì ? Hơn thua xuất phát từ nhu cầu cần được quan tâm, chứng tỏ, sở hữu mà hiện tượng là sự ghen tị, mong muốn chiếm hữu. Ta mong có được những thứ ta chưa có, những thứ ta có mà chưa nhiều, thậm chí những thứ ta có nhiều nhưng chưa thấy đủ. Dân dả mà nói là &amp;ldquo;được voi đòi tiên&amp;rdquo; hoặc &amp;ldquo;được đằng chân, lân đằng đầu&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give and Receive</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/give-and-receive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 23:06:31 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/give-and-receive/</guid>
      <description>Ask, Seek, Knock
“Ask and it will be given to you; seek and you will find; knock and the door will be opened to you. For everyone who asks receives; the one who seeks finds; and to the one who knocks, the door will be opened.
“Which of you, if your son asks for bread, will give him a stone? Or if he asks for a fish, will give him a snake?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #5</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 10:22:51 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-5/</guid>
      <description>Random comic picture While reading an article on Medium, I visited this page xkcd. It&amp;rsquo;s fanstastic website, where you can get a random comic about sarcasm, math and language everyday. And this is what I got today, https://xkcd.com/1783/
Haha, it&amp;rsquo;s cool idea, like an idea from Choose Yourself book (someday, you should try to reply 10 year-email) . It reminded me that I got some old email accounts when I was young.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sleep(60 * 60 * 8);</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/what-we-need-is-to-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 22:30:06 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/what-we-need-is-to-sleep/</guid>
      <description>What a day !
 Bank account has to be closed Forgot to turn off unused service before billing Email account get stuck in forwarding, get important emails dismissed Email sending system had been suspended because of sending a lot of bounced emails without notice Internet oversea cables got damaged, speed is slow, can&amp;rsquo;t do anything planed  Luckily, I&amp;rsquo;m still alive to feel these pains. Thank GOD, please keep giving to me your pains, everyday !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nil</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/nil/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 23:59:59 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/nil/</guid>
      <description>I lay in reality
You sit in dream
How long is distance ?
What to do if I miss ?
- Crazy guy (Han Mac Tu) -
 What to do ???
 keep walking keep writing lie myself feel tired wanna sleep     nil is always nil
and never decay in reality nor dream
 At least, we had the same thing, NIL !
Ref:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-02-28</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-02-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-02-28/</guid>
      <description>PHP Persistent connection to MySQL When a PHP process connects to MySQL server, the connection can be persistent if your PHP config has mysql.allow_persistent or mysqli.allow_persistent. (PDO has the attribute ATTR_PERSISTENT)
$dbh = new PDO(&#39;DSN&#39;, &#39;KhanhDepZai&#39;, &#39;QuenMatKhauCMNR&#39;, [PDO::ATTR_PERSISTENT =&amp;gt; TRUE]);  Object destruction PHP destruct an object automatically when an object lost all its references.
Example code:
&amp;lt;?php $x = null; function klog($x) { echo $x . &#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;; } class A { private $k; function __construct($k) { $this-&amp;gt;k = $k; } function b() { klog(&#39;[b]&#39;); } function __destruct() { klog(&amp;quot;[{$this-&amp;gt;k} has been killed]&amp;quot;); } } function c($k) { return new A($k); } function d() { c(&#39;d&#39;)-&amp;gt;b(); } function e() { global $x; $x = c(&#39;e&#39;); $x-&amp;gt;b(); klog(&#39;[e]&#39;); } function f() { klog(&#39;[f]&#39;); } d(); e(); f();  Result:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do not worry</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/do-not-worry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 20:41:11 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/do-not-worry/</guid>
      <description>No one can serve two masters. Either you will hate the one and love the other, or you will be devoted to the one and despise the other. You cannot serve both God and money.
Do Not Worry
Therefore I tell you, do not worry about your life, what you will eat or drink; or about your body, what you will wear. Is not life more than food, and the body more than clothes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random week #3</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-3/</guid>
      <description>Random game Last 2 days, my team went to play bowling. That was the first time we playing it. We had a good time to enjoy the moment playing together. The game is fun and interesting :D If you haven&amp;rsquo;t try it yet, TRY IT ASAP !!!
So what make this game interesting ?
 It&amp;rsquo;s DEAD SIMPLE, just throw the ball, that&amp;rsquo;s all It makes you feel like you throw your mood to destroy sorrowful, stressful and hateful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-02-23</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-02-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-02-23/</guid>
      <description>MYSQL UNION vs UNION ALL The difference is UNION command will sort and remove duplicated rows (RETURNED ONLY DISTINCT ROWS)
Examples :
mysql&amp;gt; select &#39;1&#39;, &#39;2&#39; union select &#39;2&#39;, &#39;1&#39; union select &#39;3&#39;, &#39;4&#39; union select &#39;1&#39;, &#39;2&#39;; +---+---+ | 1 | 2 | +---+---+ | 1 | 2 | | 2 | 1 | | 3 | 4 | +---+---+ 3 rows in set (0.00 sec) mysql&amp;gt; select &#39;1&#39;, &#39;2&#39; union select &#39;2&#39;, &#39;1&#39; union select &#39;3&#39;, &#39;4&#39; union select &#39;1&#39;, &#39;3&#39;; +---+---+ | 1 | 2 | +---+---+ | 1 | 2 | | 2 | 1 | | 3 | 4 | | 1 | 3 | +---+---+ 4 rows in set (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ở đời, cái chi là vô nghĩa ?</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/what-are-things-that-do-not-matter-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/what-are-things-that-do-not-matter-in-life/</guid>
      <description>Như đã hứa ở bài trước, hôm này mình tạo ra được 2 tiếng đồng hồ rãnh rỗi sinh nông nỗi. Đây là bản dịch của bài viết What Are Things That Do Not Matter In Life? của tác giả James Altucher. Do đây là bản dịch ngố theo phong cách lố nên nếu có sai sót thì &amp;hellip;. kệ (It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter !) 😛
Câu hỏi gốc được hỏi tại Quora : Cái méo gì là vô nghĩa ở đời ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Week #2</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-2/</guid>
      <description>Random book On Sunday night, I read a random article from Medium by James Altucher. Its title is What Are Things That Do Not Matter In Life?, I will translate it to Vietnamese when I create some free-time. It&amp;rsquo;s great article !
In article, the author led me to his book (his marketing strategy works on me). Then I bought a Kindle version on Amazon with the good price, 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2017-02-17</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-02-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-02-17/</guid>
      <description>MYSQL String problems can cause logical bugs in application Example table mysql&amp;gt; describe `test`; +------------+-------------+------+-----+-------------------+----------------+ | Field | Type | Null | Key | Default | Extra | +------------+-------------+------+-----+-------------------+----------------+ | id | smallint(6) | NO | PRI | NULL | auto_increment | | name | varchar(50) | NO | | NULL | | | created_at | timestamp | YES | MUL | CURRENT_TIMESTAMP | | +------------+-------------+------+-----+-------------------+----------------+ 3 rows in set (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to be disconnected from things ?</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/how-to-disconnected-from-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 23:59:59 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/how-to-disconnected-from-things/</guid>
      <description>In the last post &amp;ldquo;What is your Why ?&amp;rdquo;, we all know &amp;ldquo;To live is to connect&amp;rdquo;
 Connect people Connect wires Connect the Internet Connect events Connect THINGS  But, TIME will f*ck up everything from its order. It makes connected things disconnected ! It&amp;rsquo;s painful, but at least that&amp;rsquo;s called life.
We have thousand ways to disconnect from things in each context.
 In Electricity : just capping electrical wires or plug it out, &amp;hellip; In Computer Network : building a firewall then blocking packets from its source, or easier just to plug the cable out from network card, &amp;hellip; In Traveling : destroy road, bridge In Phone : blocking contact from incoming number, or change your new number, or just throw your phone out the windows In Social Networks : un-follow, un-friend, or block people from your network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Week #1</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/random-week-1/</guid>
      <description>First workday after Lunar New Year with new motivated energy, new project plan Ride to work on random roads (sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s further 3 times) Eat random foods in random places (some are good, some are the same, some causes stomach pain) Listen random songs (ascoustic, Vpop, epicmusic, edm) :  Kí Ức Mùa Đông - Bảo Trâm ft. Nguyễn Duy Phong MAI NÀY NẾU NHƯ - ANH KHANG Two Steps From Hell - I Love You Forever Vicetone &amp;amp; Youngblood Hawke - Landslide  Talk to team about current state of project, challenges and some advices :  Don&amp;rsquo;t try to do 2 things at one moment Be active !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sống đời ngẫu hứng tự nhiên - Live a random life</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/live-a-random-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 21:15:03 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/live-a-random-life/</guid>
      <description>Tiếng Việt Một năm mới lại trôi qua, tuy có nhiều chuyện thay đổi nhưng cơ bản thì &amp;ldquo;CHẰNG CÓ GÌ KHÁC CẢ&amp;rdquo;. 🙃
Vẫn là cuộc sống đó, đi làm ngày 80 tiếng (à nhầm tuần 80 tiếng), ngày ăn 3 bữa, quần cáo mặc cả ngày, đi đường nào, về đường đó (trừ lúc say có lách mấy anh Pikachu), thu nhập cũng chẳng gọi là cao, mà cũng chẳng thể bảo là nghèo, vẫn gõ 101 phím ngày qua ngày, vẫn ăn những quán quen thuộc mà cho rằng nó sạch sẽ, an cmn toàn &amp;hellip; Túm cái quần què lại là LUẨN QUẨN Ở CÁI VÒNG KHÔNG TO THÌ NHỎ !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is ur Y (why) ?</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/what-is-your-y/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/what-is-your-y/</guid>
      <description>LOVE, TIME, DEATH ! Let&amp;rsquo;s begin there,  &amp;ldquo;We long for love, we wish we had more time, and we fear death.&amp;rdquo; - (Collateral Beauty movie)
 LOVE 💖 Một năm với những trải nghiệm, cung bậc cảm xúc hỗn độn của tình yêu đưa-lối. Cuộc đời luôn trêu ta khi người yêu ta không phải người ta yêu, mà người yêu của người ta yêu thì đếch yêu ta (à nhầm !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storytelling Guide</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/storytelling-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:36:10 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/storytelling-guide/</guid>
      <description> CAS = Context -&amp;gt; Action -&amp;gt; Result Context  Where and When ? 3 questions  Who is the hero ?  real or fictitios person, place or thing (should related to your audience) or yourself  What do they want ?  worthy objective  Who or what is getting in the way ? (bad guy)  (real or fictitios) person, place or thing (should related to your audience) must be an obstacle not &amp;ldquo;larger than life&amp;rdquo; (can do anything kind)    Action:  must have context hero does battle with the villain at least on up-and-down comes to a resolution  Result :  Tell how the story ends Conveys the lesson to learn  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sử dụng Frontend Boilerplate cho việc cắt HTML Layout</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/use_frontend_boilerplate_for_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 18:12:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/use_frontend_boilerplate_for_development/</guid>
      <description>Giới thiệu Khi cắt HTML Layout từ PSD, bạn sẽ đối mặt với việc bên Design hoặc khách hàng thường xuyên yêu cầu thay đổi giao diện, thiết kế. Điều này gây ra không ít phiền nhiễu và tốn thời gian nếu cứ cập nhật hàng tá giao diện nếu sự thay đổi ảnh hưởng đến những phần layout chính (header, footer, sidebar).
Sử dụng bộ khung sườn (boiler-plate) này, sẽ giúp bạn hạn chế thao tác lặp đi, lặp lại.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2016-03-26</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2016-03-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2016-03-26/</guid>
      <description>SYSADMIN Bash shell shortcuts  Ctrl + e : jump cursor to EOL Ctrl + a : jump cursor to BOL (beginning of line) Ctrl + u : delete all from cursor to BOL Ctrl + k : delete all from cursor to EOL Ctrl + r : search history, press again for next search Ctrl + l : clear shell screen Ctrl + c : terminate the command (sometimes have to press twice) Ctrl + z : suspend the command, back to shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up PHP 7 development environment</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/setup_php7_dev_enviroment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 14:41:46 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/setup_php7_dev_enviroment/</guid>
      <description>Setup requirements Install VirtualBox  Goto https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads and download Virtualbox binary based on your OS. Install Virtualbox for virtualization  Install Vagrant  Goto https://www.vagrantup.com/downloads.html and download vagrant binary based on your OS. Install Vagrant from binary  Verify all requirements Open the terminal and try this command to verify Virtualbox is ready.
$ Virtualbox -h  Open the terminal and try this command to verify Vagrant is ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read Input Data From USB Devices in Linux</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/read_input_from_usb_keyboard_in_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 23:29:53 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/read_input_from_usb_keyboard_in_linux/</guid>
      <description>Introduction You just bought a new input device like barcode scanner, proximity card reader with USB port. And you want expose only its data to a file or send to server for processing ? But it acts like a keyboard, type the characters then trigger Enter key.
This tutorial can help you make a program can exclusive receive input data from the device and don&amp;rsquo;t affect to another program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup and Restore ElasticSearch databases using Docker</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/backup-and-restore-elasticsearch-using-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 21:07:56 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/backup-and-restore-elasticsearch-using-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction One day, your ElasticSearch data is large and you have to move all data to another nodes or you just want backup the data file to somewhere.
ElasticSearch-Dump is a tool can help you on this situation, it&amp;rsquo;s written on NodeJS so can run multi-platform. You can view the documents here.
One way more convinient if you already have Docker is running its Docker image.
Instruction Prepare a Docker image You can build manually its Docker image by</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2016-03-08</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2016-03-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2016-03-08/</guid>
      <description>PHP F-cking stupid limit of input vars Today, I tried to debug many hours to find out why my POST request missing some data (specify _token hidden field). :disappointed:
I tried to config NGINX and PHPFPM max_post_size, client_max_body_size but they still gone. After 2-3 hours searching on Google, I found the link from PHP.net, it has a config value about limiting max input vars (default = 1000), so it causes the problem about missing data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2015-12-30</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-12-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-12-30/</guid>
      <description> SYSADMIN Commands Command lsof List all opened files, sockets, pipes
Eg:
 List processes are using port 80 (need root if port between 1-1023)  # sudo lsof -i:80   List processes are using /bin/bash  # lsof /bin/bash  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP 5.6 vs PHP 7RC8 - Benchmarking using Docker</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/php5.6-vs-php7rc8-benchmarking-using-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 14:36:10 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/php5.6-vs-php7rc8-benchmarking-using-docker/</guid>
      <description>New version of PHP, PHP7 has been released yesterday after 11 years of PHP5. I am very excited with it, so I made a benchmark to compare the performance of 2 versions.
The fastest way to test out PHP multi-versions is using Docker image. You can get it from : https://hub.docker.com/_/php/
Let&amp;rsquo;s start pull PHP images docker pull php:5.6 docker pull php:7  Change directory to the web root folder of PHP project (I used my micro-framework, Sifoni to test).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2015-12-04</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-12-04/</guid>
      <description>PHP Run built-in server via Docker Docker is the fast and clean way to run Linux programs.
We can run a PHP project via PHP built-in server and Docker.
docker run -it -p 8080:8080 -v `pwd`:/code php:7 php -S 0.0.0.0:8080 -t /code/web /code/web/server.php  With server.php content is
&amp;lt;?php $filename = __DIR__.preg_replace(&#39;#(\?.*)$#&#39;, &#39;&#39;, $_SERVER[&#39;REQUEST_URI&#39;]); if (php_sapi_name() === &#39;cli-server&#39; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; is_file($filename)) { return false; } // Run application below $app = new Application(); $app-&amp;gt;run();  PYTHON Reference assign object variable When you have a object x and assign y = x, y will be a ref of x (it looks like pointer of C).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2015-12-03</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-12-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-12-03/</guid>
      <description> SYSADMIN FTP via curl tool Can upload an file via FTP by curl tool with handy script :
curl -T file_need_to_upload ftp://hostname --user user:passwd  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2015-12-02</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-12-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-12-02/</guid>
      <description>PHP Eloquent Many-to-Many Relationship To create the n-to-m relationship in Eloquent, we create a table stand between 2 tables. Eg:
We have the db schema :
   post post_tag tag     id (PK) id (PK) id (PK)   title post_id (Index) name (Unique)   content tag_id (Index)     In the model Post and Tag, we define a relation :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2015-12-01</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-12-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-12-01/</guid>
      <description>MYSQL Index is useless when use function on indexed field Reality, if using function on indexed field, you will broke indexing by accident. Eg:
WHERE MONTH(`date`) = 11 AND YEAR(`date`) = 2015  Solution is transform the query to comparison query, like this :
WHERE `date` &amp;gt;= &#39;2015-11-01&#39; AND `date` &amp;lt; &#39;2015-12-01&#39;  PYTHON String Format Unicode params unicode_thing = u&amp;quot;Xin chào mọi người&amp;quot; a = &#39;{}&#39;.format(unicode_thing)  will cause the error UnicodeEncodeError: &#39;ascii&#39; codec can&#39;t encode character u&#39;\xe0&#39; in position 6: ordinal not in range(128)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Learned - automated tool helps you learn everyday.</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/today-i-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 17:22:46 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/today-i-learned/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We constantly learn new things. This is a repo to share those learnings. TILs are short Markdown documents (a few sentences + example code) explaining concepts, bits of syntax, commands, or tips we&amp;rsquo;ve recently learned.
Today-I-Learn (TIL) is inspired by Thoughbot, TIL is a repository for everyone to share what we have learn today.
This repo has a tool that help you to manage and write down what you learned in scientific way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learned in 2015-11-30</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-11-30/</guid>
      <description>CHROME-DEV Debugging Chrome extension  To open directly the Console Dev Tools, press Cmd + Opt + J in MacOSX. To debug easily the any files of extension, open the url chrome-extension://&amp;lt;extension-id&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;file-name&amp;gt; in address bar.  MAC-OSX Shortcut keyboard improve productivity  Open the preference of any Application by Cmd + ,. Press Cmd + ~ to go previous App when switching App on Cmd + Tab Copy screenshot to clipboard by Cmd + Ctl + Shift + 3 Press Option when click to notification center is putting it on “Do no disturb” mode.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>