<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web on KhanhIceTea B(rain)-log</title>
    <link>https://khanhicetea.com/tags/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web on KhanhIceTea B(rain)-log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://khanhicetea.com/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2018-01-04 : til, web, db, mysql</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2018-01-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2018-01-04/</guid>
      <description>MYSQL Sleeping connections in MySQL When you check your MySQL process list via command show processlist;, it will show you a useful table which provide all current connection details.
&amp;ldquo;Sleep&amp;rdquo; state connections are most connection pointer waiting for the timeout to terminate. Then they still count as a connection. (Can cause MySQL connection limit error, which default equal 150 connections)
So next time, remember to close your connection before terminating your app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2018-01-03 : web, product, http, mobile, til, security</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2018-01-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2018-01-03/</guid>
      <description>HTTP Create cross-platform downloading app URL You have a mobile app for both platforms iOS and Android, each platform has different download URL. But your user doesn&amp;rsquo;t know which platform he using. Clicking wrong URL will lead to user bounce-rate.
Solution is making only 1 URL to download your app, which can redirect to right place depends on using platform. So how we achieve this ??
The key of problem is detecting user platform, which can be done by extracting the User-Agent header from http request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-12-07 : til, web, proxy, firewall</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-12-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-12-07/</guid>
      <description>WEB Using web proxy to bypass firewalls Someday, you will be blocked by a firewall while trying crawling or accessing some website. The reason is they block your IP address from accessing the server.
One solution is using a web proxy (http proxy, socks4 or socks5) to bypass the firewall, by adding the middle-man server between you and target. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit unsecured but you could use for https site only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-09-01 : sysadmin, cli, web, til, ssh, mysql, security, proxy</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-09-01/</guid>
      <description>MYSQL Mycli : a new good cli MySql Client This tool is written in Python with super cool features (auto-complete and colors).
Worth a shot !
Install
$ pip install mycli  Usage
$ mycli -h 127.0.0.1 -P 3306 -u root  Screencast
SYSADMIN Create SSH tunnel manually SSH Tunnel is a fast way to transfer traffic through unsafe internet today. It would be used in MySQL connect, FTP connect or HTTP connect, &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-08-08 : til, web, keyboard, google, linux</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-08-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-08-08/</guid>
      <description>LINUX Remap Capslock to Control key Edit file /etc/default/keyboard and set
XKBOPTIONS=&amp;quot;ctrl:nocaps&amp;quot;  Then, logout and log in again to impact
WEB Ping Google to crawl updated content When you post new content to your website, the fastest way is ping search engines to notify them. After that, they will try to crawl and index your page.
One way to ping search engines is using XMLRPC ping
This is a example XMLRPC request (HTTP POST request with xml body)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-05-18 : sysadmin, web, linux, til, error, cloudflare</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-18/</guid>
      <description>SYSADMIN Grant user to use sudo without password This is bad practice but it&amp;rsquo;s kind of hacky thing if you YOLO
# Create a user with home dir and bash shell (if you don&#39;t have yet) $ useradd -m YOURUSERNAME -s /bin/bash $ sudo vi /etc/sudoers  Add this line below root ALL=(ALL:ALL) ALL (User privilege specification section)
$ YOUR_USERNAME ALL=(ALL:ALL) NOPASSWD:ALL  Then press :wq! to force saving the file</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-04-21 : web, http, encoding, benchmark, til, tools</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-04-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-04-21/</guid>
      <description>HTTP ab failed responses When benchmarking a HTTP application server using ab tool, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t only care about how many requests per second, but percentage of Success responses.
A notice that you must have the same content-length in responses, because ab tool will assume response having different content-length from Document Length (in ab result) is failed response.
Example
Webserver using Flask
from flask import Flask from random import randint app = Flask(__name__) @app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sử dụng Frontend Boilerplate cho việc cắt HTML Layout</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/use_frontend_boilerplate_for_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 18:12:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/use_frontend_boilerplate_for_development/</guid>
      <description>Giới thiệu Khi cắt HTML Layout từ PSD, bạn sẽ đối mặt với việc bên Design hoặc khách hàng thường xuyên yêu cầu thay đổi giao diện, thiết kế. Điều này gây ra không ít phiền nhiễu và tốn thời gian nếu cứ cập nhật hàng tá giao diện nếu sự thay đổi ảnh hưởng đến những phần layout chính (header, footer, sidebar).
Sử dụng bộ khung sườn (boiler-plate) này, sẽ giúp bạn hạn chế thao tác lặp đi, lặp lại.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>