<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on KhanhIceTea B(rain)-log</title>
    <link>https://khanhicetea.com/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on KhanhIceTea B(rain)-log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://khanhicetea.com/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-11-22 : ci, git, workflow, devops, automation, til, docker</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-11-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-11-22/</guid>
      <description>DOCKER Reduce init time MySQL docker image Original MySQL docker image uses a script to generate ssl certificates for service. Sometime we don&amp;rsquo;t really need it (connect via a docker network link or need a fast enough database service to build a automated test).
We can reduce init time by removing the script from original Docker image
FROM mysql:5.7 # Remove mysql_ssl_rsa_setup to ignore setup SSL certs RUN rm -f /usr/bin/mysql_ssl_rsa_setup   FAST as a FEATURE !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Automated CI server with Drone and Docker</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/building-automated-ci-server-with-drone-and-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 17:20:46 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/building-automated-ci-server-with-drone-and-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Docker is great tool to management linux containers. It brings DevOps to next level, from development to production environment. And of course, before deploy anything to production, software should be tested carefully and automatically.
That&amp;rsquo;s why Drone, a new lightweight CI server built-on top Go lang and Docker, will help us to resolve the testing problems in simple and fast way.
Setup This guide will assume you already have Docker and Docker Compose tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2017-05-24 : til, sysadmin, docker</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2017-05-24/</guid>
      <description>DOCKER Changing channel from alpha to stable will remove ALL DATA On MacOS, changing Docker channel will remove all data (includes volumes, images, networks and &amp;hellip; everything).
Because Docker on Mac using a minimal Linux machine to host docker engine, so changing machine means discarding all old data. So BECAREFUL !
DOCKER Reducing docker image the right way When building an image, Docker engine commit file system layer on every command (RUN, ADD, COPY).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kick start Docker environment on ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/kick-start-docker-environment-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 14:19:39 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/kick-start-docker-environment-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>What does script do :
 Install latest Docker Engine Install latest Docker Compose tool AND last but not least, a congratuation message !  Here is the script :
  Hm.. it&amp;rsquo;s exactly docker images are building instead
 Ref:
 Docker meme from developermemes.com  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup and Restore ElasticSearch databases using Docker</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/backup-and-restore-elasticsearch-using-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 21:07:56 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/backup-and-restore-elasticsearch-using-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction One day, your ElasticSearch data is large and you have to move all data to another nodes or you just want backup the data file to somewhere.
ElasticSearch-Dump is a tool can help you on this situation, it&amp;rsquo;s written on NodeJS so can run multi-platform. You can view the documents here.
One way more convinient if you already have Docker is running its Docker image.
Instruction Prepare a Docker image You can build manually its Docker image by</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP 5.6 vs PHP 7RC8 - Benchmarking using Docker</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/post/php5.6-vs-php7rc8-benchmarking-using-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 14:36:10 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/post/php5.6-vs-php7rc8-benchmarking-using-docker/</guid>
      <description>New version of PHP, PHP7 has been released yesterday after 11 years of PHP5. I am very excited with it, so I made a benchmark to compare the performance of 2 versions.
The fastest way to test out PHP multi-versions is using Docker image. You can get it from : https://hub.docker.com/_/php/
Let&amp;rsquo;s start pull PHP images docker pull php:5.6 docker pull php:7  Change directory to the web root folder of PHP project (I used my micro-framework, Sifoni to test).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TIL 2015-12-04 : sysadmin, websocket, log, python, clone, ref-var, til, cli-server, docker, php</title>
      <link>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://khanhicetea.com/til/2015-12-04/</guid>
      <description>PHP Run built-in server via Docker Docker is the fast and clean way to run Linux programs.
We can run a PHP project via PHP built-in server and Docker.
docker run -it -p 8080:8080 -v `pwd`:/code php:7 php -S 0.0.0.0:8080 -t /code/web /code/web/server.php  With server.php content is
&amp;lt;?php $filename = __DIR__.preg_replace(&#39;#(\?.*)$#&#39;, &#39;&#39;, $_SERVER[&#39;REQUEST_URI&#39;]); if (php_sapi_name() === &#39;cli-server&#39; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; is_file($filename)) { return false; } // Run application below $app = new Application(); $app-&amp;gt;run();  PYTHON Reference assign object variable When you have a object x and assign y = x, y will be a ref of x (it looks like pointer of C).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>